Guide to the Elisabeth Lloyd Papers, 1954-2017 ASP.2016.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Elisabeth A. Lloyd Papers
1954-2017
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lloyd, Elisabeth
ASP.2016.01
15 Linear Feet (57 document cases)
Elisabeth Lloyd is an American philosopher of science whose work is centered in the field of philosophy of biology. The material in this archive documents her work in philosophy of biology. The materials extend over the whole of her career and include manuscript materials, working notes on articles and books in progress, professional correspondence, teaching materials, documents relating to work with professional organizations, talks given to professional audiences, as well as annotated books, manuscripts and preprints. Elisabeth Lloyd's publications include both books and professional articles.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Elisabeth Lloyd on August 1st, 2016.
Access Restrictions
Some materials are restricted for 75 years.
Arrangement
The elements of the archive are arranged into nine series, some of which are further subdivided into multiple subseries. More detailed information about the contents of each series and subseries can be found in the scope and content notes for each of the component elements. The arrangement is as follows
Series I. Correspondence, 1980-2017
Series II. Manuscripts, 1980-2017
Series III. Composition - working notes, 1980-2017
Series IV. Teaching Materials, 1980-2017
Series V. Talks to Professional Groups, 1980-2017
Series VI. Library, 1980-2017
Series VII. Conferences, 1980-2017
Series VIII. Profesional Activities, 1980-2017
Series IX. Education, 1976-1984
Scope and Content Notes
The materials in the Elisabeth Lloyd archives derive from and document the professional activities of a historian and philosopher of science. There is an extensive correspondence section, as well as manuscripts of philsophical articles written, texts of public and professional talks, teaching materials, annotated texts, manuscripts from others, and material generated by her work in professional settings such as academic societies, university administration, etc. Because her work as a philosopher and historian of science required extensive knowledge in the areas of her professional specialization, the professional correspondence is not exclusively with other philosophers. It also includes correspondence with scholars and researchers from evolutionary biology, systematics, theoretical biology and other areas in which she published extensively on philosophical issues.
Biography
Elisabeth A. Lloyd is an American historian and philosopher of science. She was born on September 3rd 1956. She attended Summit High School in New Jersey. After graduation she next attended Queen's University in 1974-1975 and in 1976 transfered to the University of Colorado, Boulder. In 1980 she earned a B.A. in Science and Political Theory; at that time she became a member of Phi Beta Kappa and attained Summa Cum Laude honors. Between 1980 and 1984 she did graduate work at Princeton University in the Department of Philosophy and in 1984 earned a Ph.D. in Philosophy from Princeton. She spent the academic year 1983 as a member of Harvard University's Graduate Program in Genetics.
Between 1985 and 1988 Lloyd was an Assistant Professor in the Department of Philosophy of the University of California, San Diego. In 1988 she took a position as Assistant Professor in the Department of Philosophy of the University of California, Berkeley. Then, In 1990, she became an Associate Professor in that Department. In 1997 she attained the rank of full Professor. While on the faculty at UC Berkeley she was also a member of the Program in Logic and Methodology. She was a member of the Berkeley department of Philosophy until 1999.
In the late 1990s she moved into a position as Professor in the Department of History and Philosophy of Science at Indiana University. She became the Arnold and Maxine Tanis Chair professor of History and Philosophy of Science during the year 2001.
Elisabeth Lloyd has been the recipient of numerous honors, awards, and fellowships as a result of her research and scholarship. She has been the recipient of multiple National Science Foundation Faculty awards, has been invited to speak in such series of distinguished lectures as the Romanell Lectures, the Central APA Dewey lecture and the Stillman Drake memorial lecture, as well as many others. In 2010, she won the Philosophy of Science Prize for one of her books.
Lloyd has published well over 70 scholarly articles on various topics in philosophy of science, evolutionary biology, and human sexuality.
Natural selection -- Philosophy; Evolution (Biology) -- Philosophy; Population genetics -- Philosophy; Human Evolution -- Philosophy; Evolution (Biology) -- Terminology; Lloyd, Elisabeth
- Correspondence, 1980 - 2014; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Correspondence series is divided into four subseries: professional, personal, university and administrative, and correspondence with manuscripts. Each section is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent, or the organization sending the letter or note. The correspondence with manuscripts contains letters from correspndents that appear in other sections, but this section keeps the manuscripts in the same folder as the letters and hence was made a separate sub-series.
  In the correspondence section there are materials from both biologists and philosophers as well as people in other academic specialties. Examples include Nancy Cartwright, Michael Donoghue, Peter Godfrey-Smith, Michael Ghiselin, Stephen J. Gould, Susan Haack, Richard Lewontin, Ernst Mayr, John McDowell, Michael Ruse, Sahotra Sarkar, Elliot Sober, and Bas Van Fraassen.
  - Professional, 1980 - 2014; 1.
    The professional correspondence section contains correspondence with other philosophers and philosophers of science such as Peter Bowler. Marion Bunge, Lyndley Darden, Susan Haack, David Hull, John McDowell, and Bas Van Fraasen, as well as with researchers in fields such as evolutionary biology, taxonomy, and systematic biology such as Michael Donoghue, Michael Ghiselin, Steven J. Gould, and Richard Lewontin,
    - Abramowitz, Shane (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abrams, Peter, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Achard, Stephanie - Cambridge University Press, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, Sonja, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Albulak, Suzanne - The Quarterly Review of Biology, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Aldrich, Michelle - Isis, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Allen, Colin, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Anderson, Carl, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Anderson, Elizabeth, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Andy (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Angel, Christine - The Quarterly Review of Biology, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Beatty, John, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Beehan, T.E. - Fellowship Committee on the Josephine de Karman Fellowship Trust, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Blankenship, Heather, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bonevac, Daniel, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Borrello, Mark, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bottrill, Joseph - Encyclopedia of Life Sciences, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Boucher, Douglas, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bowen, John, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bowler, Peter, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bradie, Michael, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Brown, Gillian, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bruce, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - BSRG Correspondence, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Buckholts, Claudia - Harvard University Press, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Buller, David, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bunge, Mario, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Burke, Susan, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Burns, Linda, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Butts, Robert E., 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Calhoun, Laurie, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Callebaut, Werner, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Cannon, Douglas, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Capek, Mary Ellen, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Capshew, James, 2001-2004 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Carlin, Ellen, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Carter, Kathryn, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Cartwright, Nancy, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Cat, Jordi, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Cate (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Clark, Austen, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Clemente, Nancy, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Coleman, Mark, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Collier, John, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Colwell, Robert K., 1988-1998 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Conee, Earl, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cormier, Harvey, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Creager, Angela, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Cronin, Helena, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Crow, James F., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Cuonzo, Margaret, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Damuth, John, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Darden, Lindley, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Davis, Parke H. - Who's Who Among America's Teachers, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Dawkins, Richard, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Deputy, Steve (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Dickie, Renée, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Dickson, Michael, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Dietrich, Michael, 1994-2004 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Doble, Jean, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Docherty, Robert - Who's Who in America, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Domski, Mary, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Donahue, John, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Donoghue, Michael, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Doris, John, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Downes, Stephen, 1998-2004 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Dronamaju, Krishna R., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Duchesneau, Francois, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Dugatkin, Lee Alan, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Earman, John, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Edquist, Charles, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Email To-Do (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Emens, Elizabeth, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Erlich, Philip, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Estlund, David, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Evans, J.M., 2007 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Fagan, Melinda, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Fausto-Sterling, Anne, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Favreau, Diane, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Feito, Jose Alfonso, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Feldman, Marcus, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ferrer, Amy E. - American Philosophical Association, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fine, Arthur, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Finkel, Steve, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fitelson, Brandon, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Flanagan, Owen, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Forber, Patrick, 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ford, Joyce - UC Berkeley Library, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Foundation Fyssen, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Francis, Richard, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Freed, Peter, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Freudenberger, Silja, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Friedman, Michael, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Frisch, Mathias, 1998-2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Fristrup, Kurt, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Garber, Daniel, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Geison, Gerald L., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Gendler, Tamar, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Getty, Gordon, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Ghins, Michel, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Ghiselin, Michael, 1993-2001 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Gigerenzer, Gerd, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Gillis, Christina M., 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Gintis, Herbert, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Godfrey-Smith, Peter, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Goodnight, Charles, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Gordon, Deborah, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Gould, Stephen Jay, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Gowen, Julie, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Grace, Adrienne, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Griesemer, James, 1987-2002 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Griffin, Angela - Oxford University Press, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Griswold Jr., Charles, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Grosh, Barbara, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Gross, Paul R., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Guralnick, Robert, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Haack, Susan, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Hackett, Edward J. - National Science Foundation, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Hahn, Roger, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Hamilton, William, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Hardcastle, Valerie, 1989-2000 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Harding, Sandra, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Harington, Robert M., 1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Harkness, Jon M. - Isis, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Harnad, Stevan, 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Harter, Margaret, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Haslanger, Sally, 1987-2002 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Heineman-Pieper, Jessica, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Hirschberg, Adam - Cambridge University Press, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Hitch, Harriet, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Hitchcock, Christopher, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Hodge, Jon, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Hoefer, Carl, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Hook, Ernest, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Howe, Hank, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Hubbard, Ruth, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Hull, David, 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Hurrell, James - National Center for Atmosphereic Research, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Indinopulos, Michael, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Irish, Stephen, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Jeffrey, Edith, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Johnson, Norma J. - Greenwood Publishing Group, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Jonathan, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Jones, Owen B., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Justus, James, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Kamin, Leon, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Kaplan, Caren, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Katz, Leonard, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Keenan, Jake Patrick, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Kerner, Ian, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Ketterson, Ellen, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - King, David, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Kirschenmann, P.P., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Klein, Alexander, 2001-2005 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Knoll, Elizabeth - The University of California Press, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Korsgaard, Christine M., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Krieling, Ken, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Krynak, Amy - The University of Chicago Press, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Kůjnstra, Herma, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Ladyman, James, 1995-2006 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Laudan, Rachel, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Lazarenko, Vladimir, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Le Strange, Ann - Greenwood Press, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Lee, Erica - Empire Who's Who Among Executive and Professional Women, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Lennox, James, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Levens, James, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Levitt, Norman, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Lewin, Nicholas, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Lewis, David, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Lewontin, Richard, 1983-2005 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Lively, Curt, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Lloyd, Elisabeth, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Loewe, Benedikt et al., 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Loftis, Rob, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Longino, Helen, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Love, Alan C., 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Lynch, Aaron, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Lynch, Lisa (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Maienschein, Jane, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Mallon, Ron, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Mancini, Diane, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Martin/Martie (?) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mary (?) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Masters, Roger, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Matthen, Mohan, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - May, Robert, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Mayr, Ernst, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mazaudon, Martine, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - McDowell, John, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - McGuire, Michael, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - McIntosh, Robert P., 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - McKiernan, Terry - United States Academic Decathalon, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - McLunes (?), Celia, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Mead, Hillary - Cambridge University Press, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Mearns, Linda, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Menahem, Ben, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Mennel, Timothy, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Mertz, Dick, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Meyers, Diana Tietjens, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Michod, Richard, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Morgan, Greg, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Morin, Donald James, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Morriston, Wesley - University of Colorado at Boulder, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Moss, Lenny, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Mullen, Sara, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Müller, Thomas, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Naples, Nancy - The Wiley-Blackwell Encyclopedia of Gender and Sexuality Studies, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Nelson, Lynn Hankinson, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Nichter, Matt, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Nickel, Bernard, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Nordmann, Alfred, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Nychka, Doug, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Odenbaugh, Jay, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Okasha, Samir, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - O'Sullivan, Lucia - International Academy of Sex Research, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Paller, Bonnie, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Paul, Diane, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Pedrocco, Sebastiano - Istituto Veneto di Scienze, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Petrov, Dmitri, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Pettorelli, Nathalie and Teplitsky, Celine, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Philosophy of Science Association miscellaneous correspondence, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Pickering, Stephan, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Platts-Mills, James, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Pollard, Paul - Lancashire Polytechnic (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Preston, John, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Publicity Department - Harvard University Press, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Rabine, Leslie, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Rains, Sara - International Biographical Centre, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Ray, Greg, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Reprint/paper requests, 1992-1997 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Richards, Bob, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Richardson, Alan, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Riskin, Jessica, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Robinson, Denis, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Rockmore, Tom, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Rohmann, Eric - Princeton University Press, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Rooney, Phyllis, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Rose, David, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Rosenberg, Alex, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Rouse, Joe, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Roush, Sherri, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Ruse, Michael, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Rust, Joshua, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Sabin, James T. - Greenwood Publishing Group, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Salzburg University (and misc. relevant papers), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Sarkar, Sahotra, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Sarkar, Sahotra and Fagan, Melinda, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Schaffner, Kenneth, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Scheiber, Harry N., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Schmidt, Claudia, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Schweizer, Vanessa, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Schwerin, Noel, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Seely, Bruce E. - Science and Technology Studies Panel for the National Science Foundation, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Sisler, William P. - Harvard University Press, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Skipper, Robert, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Skoyles, John R., 2000 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Smid, Laura and Yacavone, Daniel - The Philosophy of Science, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Sober, Elliott, 1989-2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Solomon, Miriam, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Spencer, Hamish G., 2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Spohn, Wolfgang, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Sprinkle, Robert Hunt, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Stein, Barbara R., 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Stephens, Erica, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Stephens, P.F., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Stephenson, Nicole - The University of California Press, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Sterelny, Kim, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Stewart, Sarah - W.W. Norton and Co., 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Stich, Stephen, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Stufflebean, Beth C. - Philosophical Psychology, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Sturgeon, Scott, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Subbaswamy, Kumble Ramarao, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Sumara (Sumavra), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Susko, Michael, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Symons, Don, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Tauber, Alfred, 1996-2006 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Taylor, Peter, 1988-2004 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Teller, Paul, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Terry, Jenna (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Thatcher, Sanford, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Tomášková, Silvia, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Travis, Cheryl, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Turkheimer, Eric, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Turner, Piers, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Unknown sender, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Van der Steen, Wim, 1992-1997 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Van Fraassen, Bas, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Vasan, Mildred Graham, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Wade, Michael J., 2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Wald, Ann Himmelberger - Princeton University Press, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Wallen, Kim, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Wang, William, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Ward, Cynthia, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Waters, C. Kenneth, 1989-2005 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Waters, Lindsay, 1995-2012 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Watson, Gary, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Wearing, Catherine, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Wehausen, John V., 1994 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Weisberg, Michael, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - West-Eberhard, Mary Jane, 1988-2000 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Williams, Mary, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Wilson, David (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Wilson, Margaret, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Wimbush, James C., 2001 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Winther, Rasmus, 1999-2006 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Witts, Juliet, 1997-2001 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Women's Studies Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Woodcock, Charlene - The University of California Press, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Wrangham, Richard W., 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Wright, James - Elsevier Publishing, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Wylie, Allison, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Xie, Yuyu (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Personal, 1983 - 2005; 2.
    The personal correspondence section includes letters to colleagues and friends such as David Hull, John Searle, and other people who may also appear in the Professional Correspondence sub-series. These letters lack discussion of technical philosophical or biological matters, but focus on other interests.
    - Allison, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Andler, Daniel, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Boyd, Sarah, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Campos, Luis, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Carie (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Clark, Linda Lloyd, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Cummings, Tracy, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Dar, Naomi, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Dave and Ina, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Devoe, Elizabeth Kay, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Green, Monica, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Grene, Marjorie, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Grosh, Doris, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Guy, Fred, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Hardcastle, Valerie and Gary, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Hull, David, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Irish, Steve, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Jenann, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Krutckoff, Lynne, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Lorenz, Christian (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Mapplebeckpalmer, Richard, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Marty, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - McOuat, Gordon, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Mercer, Christia, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)